### **SUMMARY**

I have taught web technologies at various colleges in Los Angeles since 2003. After taking a two-year detour into the area of CRM's and Salesforce, I refocused my skillset at General Assembly. My coding strength lies in developing responsive WordPress custom themes using modern tools.

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

CSS3, SASS, LESS, Zurb Foundation, Web Standards, Responsive Design, Twitter Bootstrap, Skeleton, Materialize, HTML5, Git, Github, Heroku, Modulus, Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails, MEAN.io, Angular, Express, Meteor JS, Creating and Consuming APIs, RESTful Web Services, JavaScript, jQuery, OOP, MVC pattern, MVVM pattern, AJAX, Gulp, Docusign, MailChimp

## **EXPERIENCE**

The Art Institute, North Hollywood CA 03/2007 – Present

- Web Developer Instructor Current Courses
  - o WordPress Custom Theming
    - Build PSD to pixel perfect custom theme
  - o Fundamentals of Programming
    - Semantic Code, HTML, Sass, CSS, JavaScript
  - o Interactive Prototype
    - Meteor JS application development
  - o Emerging Technolgies
    - Git/Github, Gulp, Sass
    - Terminal Zsh
    - Agile Development
    - Express JS, MongoDB, MEAN stack

# ElementsRe, El Segundo Hollywood CA 02/2006 – Present

- WordPress Freelance Consultant
  - Maintain five WordPress sites
  - o WordPress Custom Theming, VVV, WP-CLI, VirtualBox, Vagrant, Gulp, Sass, WordMove
  - o Git/Github

# Payment Systems Corp, Los Angeles, CA 05/2013 – 05/2015

- Salesforce Administrator
  - o Migrated data with SOQL and Data Loader and reduce license count by half saving the company over \$50,000/year.
  - o Familiarity with Apex and VisualForce
  - Implemented Company-wide training programs to improve productivity by moving away from Excel spreadsheets to using only Salesforce data
- Web Developer
  - o SEO, WordPress Custom Theming
  - Agile Environment
  - o Git and Github implementation

Created campaigns using Mailchimp

# The Art Institute, North Hollywood, CA 03/2007 - Present Adjunct Instructor (11 week courses)

- Summary of Topics and Technologies Taught 2000 Present
  - o 04/2014 Present
    - Introduction to Meteor JS to create an application locally
    - Deploying to Modulus.io, Heroku and Digital Ocean
    - Introduce efficient workflows using the Terminal, Vim, Sublime Text, Git and GitHub
    - JSON and MongoDB
    - RESTful Resources
    - Consuming APIs
  - 0 2013
    - Compare SASS, Foundation and LESS CSS frameworks
    - Introduction to CSS3
    - Workflow tools: Sublime Text and packages
    - Introduction to OOP
  - 0 2012
    - Creating web assets using Photoshop
    - Converting PSD into custom WordPress themes
    - Google fonts, Font Squirrel and web typography
    - Responsive Design
    - Web Standards and Troubleshooting Browser Incompatibilities
    - Hand Coding PHP and CRUD
  - 0 2011
    - Dom Scripting: Analysis
    - Hand Coding JavaScript versus jQuery
    - Database Concepts and SQL
    - Converting HTML to HTML5
  - 0 2010
    - Dreamweaver, PHP and CRUD
    - Installing MAMP/WAMP/XAMPP
    - Using phpMyAdmin and MySQL

# <u>Devry University</u>, Long Beach, CA 07/2012- 2015 Blended Adjunct Instructor (8 week courses)

- Summary of Topics and Technologies Taught 2000 2015
  - 0 2015
    - Sublime Text using packages and custom snippets
    - Intro to ES6 and hand-coding JavaScript
    - Adding video to web pages
    - Introduction to Meteor JS and full stack development
  - 0 2012
    - Converting PSD into custom WordPress themes
    - Introduction to Responsive Design
    - Web Standards and Troubleshooting Browser Incompatibilities

- 0 2011
  - Dom Scripting: Analysis
  - Hand Coding JavaScript versus jQuery
  - Converting HTML to HTML5
- 0 2010
  - Dreamweaver, PHP and CRUD
  - Photoshop and Dreamweaver creating and consuming web assets

# Westwood College, Los Angeles, CA 07/2003-07/2010

Full Time Instructor (10 week courses)

- Summary of Topics and Technologies Taught 2000 Present
  - 0 2010
    - Dreamweaver, PHP and CRUD
    - Installing MAMP/WAMP/XAMPP
    - Using phpMyAdmin and MySQL
  - 0 2009
    - Introduction to AJAX
    - JSON vs. XML
    - Installing WordPress locally
    - Introduction to FTP Getting Your Site Live
  - 0 2007 2008
    - Flash and ActionScript 3.0
    - Using Dreamweaver and Photoshop with Flash
  - $\circ$  2000 2006
    - Client Server Relationship
    - Hand coding HTML using Dreamweaver
    - Adding Graphics with Fireworks, DHTML and CSS

## Freelance

## Coast Music Conservatory

- Web Site Completed: 06/2013
- Technologies Used: Photoshop, HTML5, Converted existing Dreamweaver table created site to a modern Custom WordPress Theme, Responsive, Bootstrap

### TCA Architects

- Web Site Completed: 02/2013
- Technologies Used: HTML5, Bootstrap, Responsive, SASS, jQuery, Custom WordPress theme, custom JavaScript

## Pro Bono

#### *Taproot Foundation*

- Web Developer creating web sites for the following organizations:
  - o Ocean Charter School Web Site Completed 09/2012
    - Custom WordPress Theme, HTML5, jQuery
  - o Behavioral Health Services Inc. Web Site Completed 11/2011

Blog ● Twitter ● LinkedIn ● Github

- Provides various needed health services to Southern California residents.
- Photoshop, HTML5, Custom WordPress Theme, jQuery
- o North Valley Caring Services Web Site Completed 10/2010
  - Empower Low income North Hill residents to improve their communities future
  - Hand Coded HTML, CSS and 3rd Party JavaScript plugins

## **EDUCATION**

General Assembly, Web Development Immersive Program, Los Angeles, CA 06/2015 – 09/2015

- Three month immersive program learning the following technologies:
  - OOP JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Zurb and Twitter Bootstrap, Git, Github, Heroku, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails, Postgres, Node.js, Express, MEAN.io, Angular, MongoDB, Creating and consuming APIs

Temple University, Philadelphia, PA 02/2000

MBA (CIS Concentration)

Clemson University, Clemson, SC 12/1994

B.S. Financial Management